naturalwellbeing.com 2019-04-19

# NaturalWellbeing.com Privacy Policy - NaturalWellBeing.com

Your privacy is very important to us and we (Natural Wellbeing) are committed to protecting your privacy when you visit, use or perform transactions on our site. We like to make very simple for our users to understand what data is being collected and how it is used; so let us break it down for you: 

Any personal or non-personal data that we or our partners collect is exclusively used for the following 3 purposes: 

  * To be able to perform transactions, ship orders and to let users access their order history and to do other order or account related operations.
  * To diagnose issues with the website, to improve performance and user experience and to personalize the site for our users.
  * To provide consenting users with exclusive promotions, order confirmations, reminders, news and material on latest and best practices related to pets and pet care.

Your data is secured on our servers with industry standard encryption technologies and security practices and we will never share any of your personal data with any third parties without your explicit consent. 

The personal that data we collect may include, but is not limited to: your name, email address, postal address, phone number, site usage, your IP address, web browser software, billing information, survey responses and any other information you may provide about yourself to our site 

While you can choose not to provide personal data to us, but in general some personal data is required in order for you to receive relevant service offerings from us and our partners, and to enjoy benefits of being a registered member. 

####  Information you provide us 

Depending on what service offering you request on our site you may provide us with your name, email address, shipping and billing address, username on social media sites etc. These are gathered with your consent

####  Automatically shared information 

This could include your location, IP address, device information and browser software you use. These are transmitted automatically between your computer and our servers. We don’t use this data to personally identify or categorize you or your device in any way. This is primarily collected to show you the version of our website meant for your region, device category or browser software and to ensure good quality of service of our website. Our analytics partners may also collect this data to let us monitor the performance of our site. 

Cookies are small text files that are stored in your browser when you visit almost any website today. They store some basic information about your session and normally do not identify you personally. Web servers use them to communicate with your computer, personalize and improve your site experience. 

We use browser cookies for serving you dynamic content, keeping track of your shopping cart, assisting you over chat and for monitoring site usage through our analytics and advertising partners such Google, Facebook, Hotjar, Bing etc.. Please note that this is not an exhaustive list and that these partners my change from time to time. By accepting cookies on our site, you are consenting to the following kinds of cookies being set:

####  Essential cookies 

These cookies are necessary to access use our site’s functionality and features. Without these cookies, our website would not work properly and you would not be able to use several important features. For example, we use cookies to keep you logged in during your visit, so that you are not required to log in repeatedly to access different parts of the site. 

####  Analytics and advertising cookies 

These cookies are set by our analytics and advertising partners. The analytics cookies help us monitor site use and diagnose issues and areas of improvement for our site. The advertising cookies help make advertisements that you may come across on our partner sites relevant to you. Google provides a [opt-out tool](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to disable anonymous site usage data being sent to Google’s analytics services. Hotjar also has a way to disable site use data being sent through their [opt-out tool.](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out)

####  Cookie Choices 

While you reserve the right to accept cookies, we feel that the cookies set by us are either essential or beneficial to you in one way or another. If however, you choose to not accept cookies, we recommend using the browser settings and other browser-specific add-ons to manage your cookie settings for our site.

Here are links to how you can do this on some major browsers:

Lastly, most advertising networks offer you a way to opt out of advertising cookies. Please see www.aboutads.info/choices/ and www.youronlinechoices.com for useful information on how to do this. Google also provides ways to control what ads you see on Google sites: [details here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en). 

Please note that not accepting cookies on our site will likely mean that you cannot us some of the important features of the site. 

Your personal data may be stored or transferred to a country outside your own or outside the european economic area for accounting, reporting or more likely just to provide you the services offered on our site. Whenever we transfer personal data it is done in accordance to the applicable law and with appropriate safeguards.

The personal data we collect is mostly used to reliably provide you the services that you have requested from us. We do not engage in profiling our customers in any manner. We may however, use this data to personalize our offers to you based on what you may have purchased or what you may have accessed on our site.

Please note that we are not responsible for protecting any personal data that you may have knowingly made public in a product review or in any other user contributed sections of the site 

In order to revoke your consent to storage or processing of your personal data beyond processing your order please send us a deletion request as mentioned under the section “Data Retention, Access & Deletion Requests”. 

If you made a purchase with us or signed up for any of our services we retain this data so that if you do come back to shop with us again you are able to access your order history and re-order products. If you’d like access or to delete your account or any other personally identifiable data like email etc., please write to us at [customerservice@naturalwellbeing.com](mailto:customerservice@naturalwellbeing.com?subject=Data%20Access%20Request) with the subject line “Data Access Request” and we will be happy to assist you with your request. 

Most of the site use data that is collected anonymously through our analytics partners is retained for no longer 26 months. Please see the section on cookies for how to opt-out of site-use tracking. 

You have the choice to opt-out of our newsletter or other promotional emails at any time. Once you log in to your account you can go under the tab “Email Preferences” you can choose to unsubscribe to any of the email lists you had subscribed to previously. You can also use the “unsubscribe” link in the emails sent by us to be excluded from the respective email list. 

As our business evolves we may change the privacy policy. We will notify our members of changes to this Privacy Policy by either sending a notice to the email address you provided to us or by placing a notice on our website. We encourage you to check this Privacy Policy page from time to time to review the most current version.
